<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Behavior | Xiaojue Zhou</title>
    <link>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/tag/behavior/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/tag/behavior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Behavior</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 14:18:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/images/icon_huceba9e9d4a8c609672b14db0e634331f_215354_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Behavior</title>
      <link>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/tag/behavior/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What kind of words can influence our memory?</title>
      <link>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/project/wordproperties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 14:18:55 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/project/wordproperties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past studies already demonstrate strong emotional content of words improves people’s immediate recall memory and consistent colors further enhance memory(Donald et al., 2004).  It is interesting to see if same conclusion can be draw on metamemory and whether the color still interacts with emotion. If so, we can say this effect is immediate and on-line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides looking at people’s memory ability, we can also look at how people recognize this cognitive ability. Metacognition is “thinking of thinking”. Metamemory is the introspective cognition about one’s own memory ability. It is a self-judgment. While people’s natural memory capacity would restrain number of words actually remembered, words’ attributes may have larger effect on decision of one’s judgment of memory ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One hypothesis of current study is participants will remember more words when words are more familiar or easier to imagine. However, participants may not consider themselves remember (metamemory) more imaginable words but they will for more familiar words, for the reason that imageability is not very easy to identify at first impression. The current paper studies how four attributes—imageability, familiarity, emotional valence and associated colors—affect people’s ability to remember words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Factorial design is an efficient way to design experiment to quickly investigate individual variable effects, as well as the ability to study interaction effects between variables. Here I will used factorial design with repeated measure to understand the following questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypothesis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How word&amp;rsquo;s properties influence human memory ability?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does individual word&amp;rsquo;s properties influence the differences in metacognition and recall?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Stimuli.png&#34; alt=&#34;Stimuli&#34; title=&#34;StimuliColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;Example stimuli of emotional valence and color variable. Each participant received a list of 20 words and ask to remember them. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experimental-design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experimental Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;independent-variables&#34;&gt;Independent Variables&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I used 4X3 repeated measure design to study the following effects both individually and also their interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional Valence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imageability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;DesignVariables.png&#34; alt=&#34;Variables&#34; title=&#34;Variables of interest&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific design here is a full factorial design. Words’ order in each list was completely randomized. Each condition was replicated three times (three blocks) and each block contained completely randomized orders of 16 trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;DesignMatrix.png&#34; alt=&#34;Design&#34; title=&#34;DesignMatrix&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;measurements-of-memory&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurements of memory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meta-memory&lt;/strong&gt; : number of words they think they will remember. This measured subjects&amp;rsquo;s metacognition of self memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;actual recall&lt;/strong&gt; : number of words actually written down correctly. This is used to compare with meta-memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-found&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I found&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While individual ANOVA analysis of response variable &lt;em&gt;recall&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;meta-cognition&lt;/em&gt; has not shown any significant effect dependent on words&#39; properties. I further only looked at words overlap between words subjects they thought they would remember, and also they actually recalled later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Results.png&#34; alt=&#34;Result&#34; title=&#34;Results&#34;&gt;
Here I found out three $\rho &amp;lt; 0.01$ interaction effects on the items subjects both thought they would remember, and also they actually recalled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imageability and familarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imageability and colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional valence and familarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it indicated that more imagenable and familiar words lead to better memory and also made deeper impression both consciously (through meta-cognition) and also subconsciously (recall).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;participants-characteristics-by-condition&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participants characteristics by Condition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I additionally analyze how the participants use to remember words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participants used at least one strategy (9.33) remember more than participants used no strategy at all (8.125).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most participants used strategies such as association, twist letter, phonetic clues to remember words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English words with following properties made more impression:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, words in cooler colors allowed subjects to imagine those words more easily, therefore possibly increasing their memory on those words. Additionally, using a strategy was important to recall english words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resource&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My code to analyze the experiment data can be found here &lt;a href=&#34;project.Rmd&#34;&gt;(R Markdown file)&lt;/a&gt; and also on my github repository. If you want to replicate this experiment yourself, here is the materials &lt;a href=&#34;wordlist.pdf&#34;&gt;(Wordlist.pdf)&lt;/a&gt; I used to conduct this experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastination Questionnaire Construction</title>
      <link>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/project/procrastinatequestionnaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 14:18:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/project/procrastinatequestionnaire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the procrastination questionnaire is old, and subtypes of procrastination has been definied but not applied. While most people studied anxiety behind procrastination and rather used vague questions to ask individual subjects on their patterns of daily activity. I was interested in building a questionnaire specifically targeting college students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questionnaire-construction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questionnaire Construction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-the-textbook-says&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the textbook says&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Crocker &amp;amp; Algina&amp;rsquo;s textbook :  &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Classical and Modern Test Theory&lt;/em&gt;, they suggested the following steps when constructing a test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the primary purpose of the test score use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify behaviors to represent the construct
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review of research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;critical incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;direct observation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;expert judgement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instruction objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain sampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item construction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-i-wrote-the-questionnaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I wrote the questionnaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, I want to know what it means exactly by procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Procrastination definition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Procrastination is the unplanned delaying tasks and procrastinators often feel guilty about their procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Literature Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I wanted to know if any researchers has systematically studied procrastination. So I searched studies on academic procrastination and summarized their findings on procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, procrastination can be divided into two categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decisional procrastination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;behavioral procrastination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Brain Storm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After studying about procrastination study, then I visualized what a procrastinator (like myself) would do in each category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical behaviors of procrastinators are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;missing deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making decisions until last minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spend time on meaningless task before finishing task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I included questions to ask about how individuals recognize their procrastination by asking question in these two additional categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how they feel about procrastination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the reasons for procrastinations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-questionnaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My questionnaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;questionnaire.png&#34; alt=&#34;questionnaire&#34; title=&#34;Questionnaire&#34;&gt;
The current questionnaire is a self-evaluating scale focused on behavioral and decisional procrastinations in daily life and academic, reasons of procrastinations and feelings about procrastinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initially I had 50 items, then I analyzed the collected responses and end up with 25 items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5-point likert scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;population-and-sample&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population and sample&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collected responses from 25 classmates in my psychometric class, which are all graduate students in academics so it fits my desired academic population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;measuring-my-questionnaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measuring my questionnaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the following measurements to understand how effective my questionnaire is at evaluating people&amp;rsquo;s internal states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cohen&amp;rsquo;s kappa&lt;/strong&gt; : Cohen&amp;rsquo;s kappa measures the agreement between two raters who each classify N items into mutually exclusive categories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;inter-rater agreement&lt;/strong&gt; : confidence of whether the cluster I assign it to other people also assign it to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-impact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Procrastination scores were often related to lower self-regulations, lower self-efficacy, and higher neuroctism of personality trait. While most people would recognize procrastination as part of their personality, I hope this questionnaire would be their first step to identify specific behavior pattern and their general tendency to procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;improvements&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I lost the original collected data therefore cannot recover the measured statistics on individual items. This questionnaire was a psychometric class project and therefore hasn&amp;rsquo;t been widely studied in a bigger subject pool. If I have an opportunity, I would specifically collect responses from undergraduate students and see how different the response is comparing to graduate students&#39;. Also, this questionnaire was designed in 2014 and people probably procrastinate with different things with advances in technology in 2021 (2021 still sounds like future to me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are intersted in using my questionnaire, you can find the printable pdf here &lt;a href=&#34;procrastinationscale.pdf&#34;&gt;(Procrastination Survey)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How speaking a different language influneces our semantic understanding</title>
      <link>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/project/chineseword/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 14:18:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zhouxiaojue.github.io/project/chineseword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-want&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we want&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;FlowerAll.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flowers&#34; title=&#34;All Flowers belong to flower category&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In English, individual flowers are usually named with specific name of that flower (e.g., rose, tulip). However, in Chinese flowers are usually named by both the basic level name (e.g., rose, tulip) followed by subordinate level name (花, flower). For example, chamomile is named 菊花 or chamomile flower. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that Chinese native speakers categorize daily objects differently because how Chinese has built-in category information in the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we are interested in finding the priming effects of the language. First of all, we need a standardized bank of based on Chinese speakers in order to find the most representable objects inside each basic levle category (e.g., a typical dog species within dog, typical flower within flower)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-had&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What We Had&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-bank-of-stimuli&#34;&gt;A bank of stimuli&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we collected a bank of stimuli using daily objects. In the table below, each row is an picture representing a daily object. We want to know on average, if each item is named correctly and also consistenty among all the subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;DesiredOutcome.png&#34; alt=&#34;Desired bank of stimuli&#34; title=&#34;Desired bank of stimuli&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-experiment-to-observe-verbal-response&#34;&gt;Design experiment to observe verbal response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;goldRetriever.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Stimuli&#34; title=&#34;Example stimuli&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;An example stimuli&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Response.png&#34; alt=&#34;Response&#34; title=&#34;Response of stimuli&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the experiment, we asked each subject to name a total of 400 individual pictures of objects and collected over 30 subjects&#39; verbal response to each picture, as well as how fast they name the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;measurements-of-individual-items&#34;&gt;Measurements of individual items&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each item (picture), we calculated the following statistics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entropy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average naming accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total number of different labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average response time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-found&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What We Found&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is still an ongoing project, we have established the bank of 285 individual pictures of daily animals and daily objects, each comes with the following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardized Chinese name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corresponding English names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item&amp;rsquo;s basic semantic level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item&amp;rsquo;s surordinate level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average Response time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entropy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in collaboration, please contact halleycl at gmail dot com. We would love to have people use this stimuli bank!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
